DENTON WARNOCK

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Engineer focused on team collaboration, maximizing efficiency, and making meaningful contributions. Prior insurance professional with over six years experience building relationships, working on teams, and finding creative solutions to problems. Launched an employee benefits division, continually learned new insurance products, created successful marketing campaign, and lead benefit meetings to enroll new members.

EDUCATION

Lambda School Academy of Computer Science and Web Development

July 2019 - Current

Full Stack Web Development 2020

Completed all curriculum course work including: React, Redux, Node, Express, SQL, JavaScript, CSS/SCSS/LESS, HTML (https://lambdaschool.com/courses/full-stack-web-development)

Utilized agile software development and Git workflow on all projects.

Developed code in team environment, pair programmed, and reviewed all team members pull requests.

California State University, Sacramento Bachelor of Science Business Finance 2006 2002 - 2006

EMPLOYMENT

Leaders Choice Insurance Services, Sacramento, CA, Licensed Health Insurance Agent - Customer Service Representative, Sacramento, CA

2013 - 2019

Spearheaded employee benefits division, enrolling hundreds in personalized health insurance plans. Managed account servicing for largest commercial clients in agency with rapid response times.

PT Gaming, Casino Gaming Associate - Supervisor, Sacramento, CA

2009 - 2012

Enforced all casino game rules were followed and payouts were accurate. Maintained strict logs of all money flows and totals.

Tested employees on speed and accuracy abilities for monitoring games. Summarized daily events to management and supervisors with a written report.

SKILLS

TECHNICAL SKILLS: JavaScript, React/Hooks, Redux, Node.js/Express, SQL/Sqlite3, Knex.js, API, HTML5, CSS3/SASS, Git & GitHub, UI/UX, Responsive Design

PROJECTS

Fresh Finds Farmers Market - Front End

Dec. 2019 - Jan. 2020

Oct. 2019 - Oct. 2019

Created wire frames for page layouts, and component flow chart for state management.

Consulted with back end developer to help create data points for users, farms, farmers, and produce.

Used JWTs to handle login authentication for different user types.

Built login, register, famer-dashboard, user-dashboard, shopping cart, view orders, and create-update-delete item forms using React components.

https://github.com/Farm-Fresh-Produce-Build-Week/The-Real-Front-End

Saltiest Trolls of Hacker News

Web App using sentiment analysis to find the most negative comments on Hacker News website.

Planned Front End interface and data flow with team of 4 developers.

Integrated search by username functionality to data feed.

Implemented ability to favorite comments and edit username information.

https://github.com/Build-Week-Saltiest-Hacker-News-Trolls

Crypto Tracker - Dark Mode

Sept. 2019 - Sept. 2019

Crypto Price tracking site that uses Coin Gecko API.

Created custom hook in React to persist dark mode settings in local storage.

Added links to detailed pages of each coin with React Router for fluid single page application design.

https://github.com/DentonWarnock/dark-mode

Party Planner - User Interface

Aug. 2019 - Aug. 2019

Designed and built fully responsive User Interface with HTML/LESS.

Utilized CSS Flexbox and Grid with media queries for layouts of most common screen sizes.

https://github.com/party-planner-pt/BW-PT-PartyPlanner-UI-DW

ACTIVITIES

Hacktoberfest - 5+ open source contributions